Protect Your Majesty
陛下をお守りする
Your Majesty
陛下
Quack doctors
下手な医者
They're all quacks
みんな名医じゃない
Drag them all out and behead them
彼らは皆私のために引きずり出され首を切られました
General, spare us
将軍命だけはお助けください
Your Majesty's injury has reached the internal organs
陛下は心の奥底まで傷つけられました
Coupled with years of managing state affairs
さらに長年にわたり国事に努めてきたことも重なって
And recent continuous battles
最近また連続して大きな戦いが起きている
Now Your Majesty's body is exhausted
今陛下の体は疲れ果てています
We truly are powerless
私たちは本当に無力です
Forget it
やめておこう
Don't trouble them
彼らを困らせないでください
Your Majesty
陛下
Find someone
人を探す
Keep them under guard
彼らを監禁しなさい
No one may contact them
誰も触れてはいけない
Yes
はい
Also
まだ
From now on
今から
Without my permission
朕の許可なしで
Anyone
誰でも
May not approach the tent
大きなテントに近づいてはいけません
Within ten zhang
十丈以内
What if the two generals come to request an audience?
もし二人の将軍が面会を求めに来たらどうするのですか
You say
あなたが言って
I
朕
Am exhausted from marching
行軍で疲れる
Everything
すべて
Will be discussed upon return to court
朝になってから再び話そう
Now
今では
The central plains are settled
中原はすでに安定している
Shilang is dead
石の狼は死んだ
Our dynasty
私の朝
Has no more worries
これでもう後顧の憂いはない
Soldiers
将校たち
Should go home
そろそろ家に帰る時間だ
First month of the 27th year of Longwu
隆武二十七年の元旦
You issue an edict
あなたは命令を発布する
Ordering the Second Prince Sikong Xu to continue guarding Yan Bei
命じて二皇子の司空旭に燕北の駐守を続けさせる
The rest of the army returns to court
残りの大軍は帰還して朝廷に戻った
When reaching the Shuoyang County area
烁阳郡の一帯まで行く
The weather became increasingly cold
しかし天気はだんだん寒くなってきた
You had to rest temporarily in Yiyang City
あなたは弋陽城で一時的に立ち止まらざるを得ない
Your Majesty
陛下
The weather is too cold
天気がとても寒い
Not suitable for long outings
長く外出すべきでない
Your health is important
龍の体は重いな
Have they all arrived?
みんな来ましたか
Yes
来た
The people you wish to summon
あなたが呼びたい人
Are all in the city awaiting your order
今はすべて都で命令を待っています
Good
はい
At this time, the city lord's residence
この時の城主府
Has been converted into your temporary residence
すでにあなたの一時的な居住地に改造されました
All your affairs are managed here
あなたのすべての用事もここで処理されています
Years of warfare
多年にわたる戦い
Your hair has actually shown some silver
あなたの髪に少し銀色が見えるなんて
Though physically weak
体は虚弱でありながら
Your eyes still shine with light
でもあなたの目にはまだ輝きが宿っている
You know your time is running out
あなたは自分の余命があまり長くないことを自覚している
But the newly pacified realm
しかしようやく平定された天下
Cannot fall into chaos again because of your departure
あなたの去り方のせいでこれ以上混乱することはできない
You must handle everything that follows
あなたはこれからのすべてをしっかり処理しなければなりません
Your Majesty
陛下
Issue orders
伝令